hello today we are gonna be discussing
Orson Welles and William Randolph Hearst
William Randolph Hearst was the biggest
media mole in America three out of five
people read a Hearst paper he had owned
25% of the world's most valuable art the
second biggest private zoo in the world
he had started to build San Simeon the
property was like half the size of Rhode
Island man not his wife but this woman
Marion Davies next thing you know she's
living in San Simeon loving it
meanwhile Orson Welles a boy genius
prodigy had just done War of the Worlds
Orson would say things like judge 7:52
p.m. we've spotted a craft entering
Earth's atmosphere it lands on the White
House lawn yes yes Hollywood came on
knocking and they said Orson babe what
do you want bed you wanna you want a
three-picture deal we don't say a word
all the money what bet Tom greenlit done
deal
whoresons having some late-night
probably hammered cocktails with a one
Herman mankiewicz screenwriter and
mankiewicz all sudden starts going like
that was a that was at San Simeon the
other week it worsens like you have
inside info in like juicy tidbits of
what's happening at the Hearst Castle
he's like oh yeah he's like oh I have an
inside guy do tell do tell I party there
regularly I'm having drinks smoking cigs
string and champagne
having delicious appetizers with Marion
Davies and Dougie Fairbanks and all
those people loving it he's witnessing
this stuff firsthand of oh hello sir
whisky bird oh but then Hearst would
leave these parties and go out and
spread all the newspapers out and just
he lured over his powers like I control
media which controls the world
I am in God and Orson to stop
I need you to write me a screenplay
about this and I am going to make it
into a feature film
[Music]
deal was made orson welles knew that we
need to kind of keep this top secret to
keep it under wraps because of hearst
mankiewicz would pound out the pages
orson welles kept on reading the stuff
he's like this is amazing screen reading
this is gonna be the best movie ever got
making a Shh kickass a little bit
Capisce he wrote produced directed he
starred in it when the movie was
completes the most powerful gossip
columnist of the time she said to Hearst
they made Marion Davies look like a
complete floozy horrible person I mean
did the whole movie was basically
trashing the Hearst name Hearst hears
about this and he sees red he starts
threatening any newspaper out there if
you put a review if you put an ad out
for this you're done he told every movie
theater if you run this movie we will
never place an ad for one of your films
ever again so
[Music]
Oh talk about Citizen Kane so RKO called
Orson Welles and 2:00 in the morning and
said Orson no one is going to show your
film wonderful show it intense put up a
quote that says the movie that no one
will let you see as fate would have it
Orson and William Randolph Hearst were
in the same elevator wells and Hearst
never look at each other
Orson says so mr. Hearst
did you see my film they said no they
never will and he said Kane would have
seen it
Kane would have seen the film they got
nominated for nine Academy Awards they
won one Oscar for Best Screenplay while
they were in nuff Hurst hated loathe and
one to crush the movie but that's where
his legacy is remembered as Kane is a
great movie dude is haunting and there's
nothing like that movie at all
there's nothing will ever be like a
movie there's such a wonderful thing I
love it and he would also did the voice
and the Transformers movie
you